JOACHIM HODANA

JUNIOR PYTHON DEVELOPER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Szubin/Bydgoszcz Poland

EMAIL

me@joachimhodana.com

DATE OF BIRTH

02/01/2005

LINKS

github.com/style77 joachimhodana.com codenerds.tech

SKILLS

Python

React

Docker

SQL

Git

Typescript

Django

Fastapi

Celery

CI/CD

Unit/integration tests

LANGUAGES

Polish

• • • • •

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

PROFILE

I am a passionate developer who started coding at the age of 13. As a self-taught programmer, I quickly grasp new technologies and frameworks. While I have experience with frontend frameworks like Vite, React, and Next, my true passion and preference lie in backend development, especially using Python and Go.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Python Developer, Decision Sciences AI

Remote

Nov 2022 — May 2023

Created data analysis pipelines for insurance prices prediction software using Python & data tools. Extracted, cleaned & analyzed data to derive valuable insights, improving efficiency & risk assessment. Used Pandas, Numpy & Postgresql.

Freelancer

Oct 2022 — Present

Used web technologies, Python, a bit of PHP, and a lot more to deliver products for clients. Developed many websites, APIs and worked with teams to deliver apps with great code quality

EDUCATION

Teleinformatics Technician, Zespół Szkół Elektronicznych

Bydgoszcz

Oct 2019 — Apr 2024

PROJECTS

Skynotes

Dec 2023 — Present

Cloud storage developed using DRF and React, integrating microservices through gRPC, such as a thumbnailer - a service for creating thumbnails for files written in Go. Utilized Celery with RabbitMQ for file handling. All of that stacked in one docker-compose for easy one-click deployment.

code: github.com/style77/skynotes

Dealscan

Nov 2023 — Dec 2023

Car offers aggregator written in Django with HTMX, alpine.js. Integrated Stripe for payments.

code: github.com/style77/dealscan

demo: dealscan.joachimhodana.com

Quantex

Jul 2023

Powerful trading bot with ChatGPT sentiment analysis of news headlines. Inspired by a paper released by Alejandro Lopez-Lira and Yuehua Tang from the University of Florida. Used FastAPI to create an API for storing all the data for future use and connected a Telegram bot to automatically send the analysis.

code: github.com/style77/quantex

Newsltr.io

Oct 2023 — Present

The Newsltr is a SaaS web application, serving as a newsletter manager developed using DRF and React, integrating Stripe for payments and AWS SES for email delivery. I took charge of leading the team, as we operated within a four-person team.

code: github.com/style77/newsltr

Streamx

Jun 2023 — Jul 2023

Live streaming platform written in Django, Next.js with use of Nginx-rtmp module to forward HLS streams - Includes validation with stream keys and allows users to stream from OBS Studio.

code: github.com/style77/streamx

REFERENCES

Marek Balcerzak from Decision Sciences Al

marek.balcerzak@decisionsciences.ai

INTERNSHIPS

Network Engineer internship, LOGON S.A.

Bydgoszcz

Jan 2022 — Feb 2022

School internship, I were responsible for creating networks around the office to learn how they work. I also worked with IP cameras and other network-related devices.

Helpdesk & PHP developer, Zakład Informatyki Stosowanej

Bydgoszcz

May 2023 — Jun 2023

Developed a customized ticket report user interface (UI) using PHP – it was my initial experience with the language. I used to visit clients to handle hardware and software repairs provided by the company.